我们都因彼此而经受过苦难
We have suffered at each other's hands.
也因互相争斗而失去挚爱
We have lost people we love at each other's hands.
这不是贵族与贵族间的战争
This isn't about noble houses,
这是活人和死人的战争
this is about the living and the dead.
而我打算待在活人中间
And I intend to stay amongst the living.
《权力的游戏》
前情回顾
我给你个选择的机会
I offer you a choice.
屈膝称臣 为我效力
Bend the knee and join me,
或者拒不从命 死路一条
or refuse, and die.
她来到维斯特洛是为了夺回七大王国
She is here to reclaim the Seven Kingdoms.
而北境正是七国之一
The North is one of those seven kingdoms.
夜王的大军一天天壮大起来
The Night King's army grows larger by the day.
我们需要盟友 强大的盟友
We need allies. Powerful allies.
这些怪物的确存在
The monsters are real.
龙 异鬼 多斯拉克哮吼武士……
Dragons, White Walkers, Dothraki screamers...
就让这些怪物自相残杀吧
Let the monsters kill each other.
剩下的残局就留给我们来收拾
We will deal with whatever is left.
我们将同心协力
We are going to destroy the Night King
消灭夜王和他的军队
and his army, and we'll do it together.
他宣誓为丹妮莉丝·坦格利安而战
He pledged to fight for Daenerys Targaryen.
他已经屈膝称臣了
He's bent the knee.
他需要知道真相
He needs to know the truth.
琼恩不是我父亲的亲生儿子
Jon isn't really my father's son.
他是雷加·坦格利安
He's the son of Rhaegar Targaryen,
和我姑妈莱安娜·史塔克之子
and my aunt, Lyanna Stark.
他是铁王座的继承人
He's the heir to the Iron Throne.
我们要告诉他
We need to tell him.
同样的事情也会发生在我们身上……
The same thing is coming for all of us...
迫在眉睫
And it is here.
m -11 -35 l -11 39 l 63 39 l 63 -35
m -86 -116 b -89 -117 -89 -117 -95 -119 l -97 -115 l -85 -105 l -116 -102 b -116 -100 -116 -98 -116 -97 l -108 -91 l -96 -91 l -116 -63 l -105 -69 l -96 -47 l -74 -63 l -77 -69 l -91 -63 l -91 -77 l -88 -80 l -66 -49 l -46 -63 l -58 -66 l -66 -74 l -49 -80 l -60 -91 l -74 -83 l -80 -91 l -77 -94 l -46 -94 l -52 -108 l -71 -105 b -69 -107 -67 -110 -66 -113 m -31 -119.875 l -33 -119 b -34 -113 -36 -107 -38 -102 l -46 -97 b -42 -93 -38 -89 -35 -85 l -44 -63 b -41 -64 -38 -65 -35 -66 l -35 -52 l -33 -47 l -27 -55 l -27 -69 l -21 -63 l -21 -69 l -19 -72 l -27 -88 l -21 -94 l -21 -99 l -27 -102 l -27 -102 l -30 -116 m -21 -113 l -21 -105 l -21 -99 l -21 -94 l -19 -85 l -19 -66 l -21 -49 l -19 -47 l -7 -52 l 26 -52 l 18 -66 l -7 -63 l -5 -69 l 6 -69 l 18 -69 l 20 -99 l -7 -94 l -7 -83 l 6 -85 l 6 -80 l -7 -77 l -7 -94 l -10 -99 l 23 -102 l 18 -116 l -10 -110 l -19 -116 m -105 -38 l -116 -41 l -110 -13 l -102 -19 l -102 -30 l -63 -33 l -55 -19 l -46 -41 l -49 -44 m -88 -33 l -91 -24 l -99 -24 l -105 -16 l -102 -13 l -85 -16 l -85 -10 l -94 -8 l -85 -16 l -102 -13 l -108 1 l -88 1 l -88 4 l -116 6 l -116 9 l -110 15 l -88 15 l -85 26 l -77 23 l -74 15 l -52 15 l -49 15 l -52 4 l -74 6 l -71 1 l -55 -2 l -60 -13 l -74 -10 l -74 -13 l -55 -16 l -63 -24 l -74 -24 l -80 -33 m -46 -41 l -38 -2 l -41 23 l -38 26 l 1 20 l 15 26 l 18 23 l 18 -8 l 20 -41 l 20 -44 l -24 -38 l -35 -41 l -35 -30 l -13 -30 l -19 -21 l -33 -19 l -33 -13 l -21 -13 l -33 6 l -33 15 l -13 -5 l -13 1 l -21 6 l -13 12 l -2 9 l -2 -8 l 9 -10 l 12 -19 l 1 -21 l -2 -27 l 9 -33 l 6 -16 l 6 -10 l 9 12 l -2 9 l -30 12 l -30 12 l -27 -2 l -27 -2 l -30 -16 l -27 -21 l -35 -41 m -126 -127 l -130 -130 l -129 38 l 34 37 l 35 -135 l -130 -131 l -127 -127 l 30 -129 l 31 32 l -124 34
最专业冰火字幕
诚意奉献
翻译 熊岛莱安娜
绝境长城  the Wall
翻译 玫瑰叔
翻译 芹泽多摩熊
翻译 Ashara_C
翻译 林顿
最后壁炉城Last Hearth
翻译 叽拇啾
最专业的华语冰火资料站：        冰与火之歌中文维基
https://asoiaf.huijiwiki.com
m 31 -6 l -21 40 l 34 22 m 29 -8 l -3 -12 l -24 40
临冬城Winterfell
校对 托曼
校对 北落师门
后期 依依Eva
监制 临冬城的狮子
监制 北落师门
临冬城的地窖Crypt of Winterfell
联合出品
史诗图书 | 冰火中文维基 | 黑城堡奇幻微刊
Epic Books         ASOIAF.huijiwiki.com          Heichengbao
特别顾问 屈畅(ccxx)@史诗图书
君临 King's Landing
字幕组发起人 baozhenyuawabi
策划 衣柜军团
史诗图书  正统奇幻的圣殿
红堡Red Keep
根据长篇小说
《冰与火之歌》 改编
原著  乔治·R·R·马丁
权力的游戏
衣柜字幕组
m -18.625 0 l -18.625 0 l 281.25 0 l 281.25 1.125 l -18.625 1.125
m -86 -116 b -89 -117 -89 -117 -95 -119 l -97 -115 l -85 -105 l -116 -102 b -116 -100 -116 -98 -116 -97 l -108 -91 l -96 -91 l -116 -63 l -105 -69 l -96 -47 l -74 -63 l -77 -69 l -91 -63 l -91 -77 l -88 -80 l -66 -49 l -46 -63 l -58 -66 l -66 -74 l -49 -80 l -60 -91 l -74 -83 l -80 -91 l -77 -94 l -46 -94 l -52 -108 l -71 -105 b -69 -107 -67 -110 -66 -113 m -31 -119.875 l -33 -119 b -34 -113 -36 -107 -38 -102 l -46 -97 b -42 -93 -38 -89 -35 -85 l -44 -63 b -41 -64 -38 -65 -35 -66 l -35 -52 l -33 -47 l -27 -55 l -27 -69 l -21 -63 l -21 -69 l -19 -72 l -27 -88 l -21 -94 l -21 -99 l -27 -102 l -27 -102 l -30 -116 m -21 -113 l -21 -105 l -21 -99 l -21 -94 l -19 -85 l -19 -66 l -21 -49 l -19 -47 l -7 -52 l 26 -52 l 18 -66 l -7 -63 l -5 -69 l 6 -69 l 18 -69 l 20 -99 l -7 -94 l -7 -83 l 6 -85 l 6 -80 l -7 -77 l -7 -94 l -10 -99 l 23 -102 l 18 -116 l -10 -110 l -19 -116 m -105 -38 l -116 -41 l -110 -13 l -102 -19 l -102 -30 l -63 -33 l -55 -19 l -46 -41 l -49 -44 m -88 -33 l -91 -24 l -99 -24 l -105 -16 l -102 -13 l -85 -16 l -85 -10 l -94 -8 l -85 -16 l -102 -13 l -108 1 l -88 1 l -88 4 l -116 6 l -116 9 l -110 15 l -88 15 l -85 26 l -77 23 l -74 15 l -52 15 l -49 15 l -52 4 l -74 6 l -71 1 l -55 -2 l -60 -13 l -74 -10 l -74 -13 l -55 -16 l -63 -24 l -74 -24 l -80 -33 m -46 -41 l -38 -2 l -41 23 l -38 26 l 1 20 l 15 26 l 18 23 l 18 -8 l 20 -41 l 20 -44 l -24 -38 l -35 -41 l -35 -30 l -13 -30 l -19 -21 l -33 -19 l -33 -13 l -21 -13 l -33 6 l -33 15 l -13 -5 l -13 1 l -21 6 l -13 12 l -2 9 l -2 -8 l 9 -10 l 12 -19 l 1 -21 l -2 -27 l 9 -33 l 6 -16 l 6 -10 l 9 12 l -2 9 l -30 12 l -30 12 l -27 -2 l -27 -2 l -30 -16 l -27 -21 l -35 -41 m -126 -127 l -130 -130 l -129 38 l 34 37 l 35 -135 l -130 -131 l -127 -127 l 30 -129 l 31 32 l -124 34
协力制作
史诗图书
Epic Books
ASOIAF.huijiwiki.com
冰火中文维基
黑城堡
EPICASTLE
第一集
临冬城
Winterfell
本字幕的制作目的是为了相关爱好者交流学习之用，
请在下载24小时之内删除。请勿用于任何商业用途。
艾莉亚·史塔克
琼恩·雪诺
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安
“龙之母”
桑铎·克里冈
“猎狗”
詹德利
“大牛”
提利昂·兰尼斯特
“小恶魔” 丹妮莉丝的首相
你该为自己感到幸运
You should consider yourself lucky.
瓦里斯
至少你的蛋蛋不会被冻掉
At least your balls won't freeze off.
别人拿侏儒开玩笑 你就生气
You take great offense at dwarf jokes,
结果你又老是开阉人的玩笑 你怎么这样？
but love telling eunuch jokes. Why is that?
因为我有蛋蛋 你没有
Because I have balls, and you don't.
灰虫子
无垢者指挥官
弥桑黛
丹妮莉丝的翻译及顾问
我提醒过你
I warned you.
北方人不怎么信任外来者
Northerners don't much trust outsiders.
卓耿
丹妮莉丝的黑龙
珊莎·史塔克
临冬城公爵夫人
布兰·史塔克
绿先知
瞧
Look at you.
你长成男子汉了
You're a man.
差不多算是吧
Almost.
乔拉·莫尔蒙
“大熊”
戴佛斯·席渥斯
“洋葱骑士”
- 艾莉亚呢？- 不知道躲哪去了
-Where's Arya? -Lurking somewhere.
这是坦格利安家族的丹妮莉丝女王
Queen Daenerys of House Targaryen.
这是我的妹妹 临冬城公爵夫人 珊莎·史塔克
My sister, Sansa Stark, the Lady of Winterfell.
史塔克夫人 感谢你邀请我们来到你家
Thank you for inviting us into your home, Lady Stark.
北境正如你哥哥所描绘的那样美丽
The North is as beautiful
你也如北境的风光一样美丽动人
as your brother claimed, as are you.
临冬城效忠于您 陛下
Winterfell is yours, Your Grace.
我们现在没有时间聊这些
We don't have time for all this.
夜王已经转化了您的龙 它成了尸鬼
The Night King has your dragon. He's one of them now.
长城已破
The Wall has fallen,
亡者大军正向南行进
the dead march south.
一听到长城倒塌的消息
As soon as we heard about the Wall,
我就召集了所有的封臣 撤退到临冬城
I called all our banners to retreat to Winterfell.
安柏大人……
Lord Umber...
你的人什么时候到？
when can we expect your people to arrive?
奈德·安柏
最后壁炉城伯爵
我们需要更多的马匹和马车 希望夫人允许
We need more horses and wagons, if it please my lady.
以及大人……
And my lord.
和女王陛下允许 抱歉
And my queen. Sorry.
我们将为你倾囊相助
You'll have as many as we can spare.
尽快回到最后壁炉城 带你的人过来
Hurry back to Last Hearth and bring your people here.
我们还需要放出渡鸦 把消息传给守夜人
We need to send ravens to the Night's Watch as well.
现在还在这些城堡驻扎已经毫无意义了
There's no sense in manning the castles anymore.
我们要守住这里
We make our stand here.
马上去办 陛下
At once, Your Grace.
“陛下”
"Your Grace."
莱安娜·莫尔蒙
熊岛伯爵夫人
现在您已经不是陛下了 对吧？
But you're not. Are you?
您离开临冬城的时候还是北境之王
You left Winterfell a king
可回来时候却是一位——
and came back a--
我不太清楚您现在的身份到底算什么
I'm not sure what you are now.
公爵大人？
A lord?
或者您现在什么都不是？
Nothing at all?
- 这不重要 - 不重要？
-It's not important. -Not important?
曾经 我们可是拥立您为北境之王
We named you King in the North.
北境之王呐！
King of the North!
确实 夫人
You did, my lady.
那曾经是我人生中的荣光
It was the honor of my life.
我将永远对你们的信任感念于心
I'll always be grateful for your faith.
但当初我离开临冬城的时候
But when I left Winterfell,
我告诉过大家我们需要盟友 否则我们只有死路一条
I told you we need allies or we will die.
而现在我把盟友带回了家
I have brought those allies home
与我们并肩作战
to fight alongside us.
我必须做出选择
I had a choice,
是保住我的王位还是保住北境
keep my crown or protect the North.
我选择了北境
I chose the North.
我们当中 要是有人能在接下来这场大战中活下来
If anyone survives the war to come,
那就得感谢琼恩·雪诺
we'll have Jon Snow to thank.
他冒着生命危险 证明威胁我们的东西是真实存在的
He risked his life to show us the threat is real.
多亏了他的勇气
Thanks to his courage,
我们才能带来
we have brought with us the greatest army
有史以来最强大的军队
the world has ever seen.
我们才能带回两条成年巨龙
We have brought two full-grown dragons.
很快 兰尼斯特家族的军队
And soon, the Lannister army
就会行军北上加入我们
will ride north to join our cause.
我知道 我知道 我们家族
I know, I know, our people
一直也算不上北境的盟友
haven't been friends in the past.
但我们现在必须携手作战……
But we must fight together now...
否则我们都会死
or die.
我想问一下 我们该怎么供给
May I ask,how are we meant to feed
这支有史以来最强大的军队呢？
the greatest army the world has ever seen?
我能确保我们的存粮能撑过这个冬天
While I ensured our stores would last through winter,
但我可没有料到还要给多斯拉克大军
I didn't account for Dothraki,
无垢者 甚至两条成年巨龙做准备
Unsullied and two full-grown dragons.
对了 龙吃什么？
What do dragons eat, anyway?
想吃什么就吃什么
Whatever they want.
嘿 注意点 小子 一丁点儿也不能漏掉
Hey, careful, lads.We need every last bit of it.
抱歉
Sorry 'bout that.
这是最后一车了吗？
Are these the last of the wagons?
是的
Aye.
好吧 全都推去锻造处
All right, let's get it all to the forges.
大人
My lord.
约恩·罗伊斯
“青铜约恩” 谷地领主
夫人
My lady.
我先退下了
临冬城公爵夫人
The Lady of Winterfell.
这头衔不错啊
Has a nice ring to it.
女王之手也不错
So does Hand of the Queen.
这得看是哪位女王了
Depending on the queen, I suppose.
我们上次谈话 还是在乔佛里的婚礼上
Last time we spoke was at Joffrey's wedding.
- 真是不幸 - 总归有它的意义
- Miserable affair.- It had its moments.
我很抱歉就那样离开了
Apologies for leaving like that.
的确 有点难以解释
Yes,it was a bit hard to explain
为什么在国王被谋杀后 我的妻子就逃跑了
why my wife fled moments after the king's murder.
但我们现在都还活着
We both survived.
许多人低估了你
Many underestimated you.
他们当中 大部分都已经死了
Most of them are dead now.
听到兰尼斯特大军北上的消息
I'm sure you weren't thrilled to hear
你应该并不高兴吧
the Lannister army's marching north.
你对我姐姐的恐惧可以理解
You have every right to be fearful of my sister.
没人比我更怕她
No one fears her more than I do.
- 但我一定会确保你的安全—— - 瑟曦跟你说
- But I promise, you'll be safe---Cersei told you her army
她的军队会来北境为你作战？
was coming north to fight for you?
是的
She did.
你也信了？
And you believed her?
她现在有了活下去的动力
She has something to live for now.
我相信她是想活着的
I believe she wants to survive.
我还以为你是世界上最聪明的人
I used to think you were the cleverest man alive.
你以前看起来更高一些
You used to be taller.
你怎么跟到我的？
How did you sneak up on me?
你不是被一剑穿心了吗 你是怎么活下来的？
How did you survive a knife through the heart?
其实我当时已经死了
I didn't.
你还留着它
You still have it.
缝衣针
Needle.
你用过它吗？
Have you ever used it?
一两次吧
Once or twice.
瓦雷利亚钢剑
Valyrian steel.
羡慕吗？
Jealous?
对我来说太沉了
Too heavy for me.
你之前去哪儿了？
Where were you before?
你可以帮我跟珊莎说说好话的
I could've used your help with Sansa.
她不喜欢你的女王 对吧？
She doesn't like your queen,does she?
珊莎觉得她比谁都聪明
Sansa thinks she's smarter than everyone.
她是我遇到过的最聪明的人
She's the smartest person I've ever met.
你是在保护她吗？
Now you're defending her?
是吗？
You?
我保护的是我们的家族
I'm defending our family.
她也一样
So is she.
是啊
Yeah.
我也是她的家人
I'm her family too.
别忘了这一点
Don't forget that.
科本
瑟曦的首相
陛下 恐怕我带来了个坏消息
Your Grace, I'm afraid I bring terrible news.
瑟曦
铁王座上的女王
亡者大军已经攻破长城了
The dead have broken through the Wall.
好
Good.
哈利·斯崔克兰
黄金团团长
攸伦·葛雷乔伊
铁群岛之王
亚拉·葛雷乔伊
不如你就干脆一点杀了我吧
Why don't you just get it over with and kill me?
我们可是一家人
But we're family.
葛雷乔伊家族仅剩的几个
The last Greyjoys left in the world.
或者说 仅剩的几个有种的
The last ones with balls anyway.
我要是杀了你……
If I kill you...
还跟谁说话去？
who can I talk to?
嗯？
Hmm?
我的船员都是哑巴
I've got a crew full of mutes.
在海上 人就容易寂寞
It gets lonely at sea.
我们这是到了君临？
Are we in King's Landing?
嗯
Mm.
你选错边了
You picked the losing side.
那我就带着铁舰队去别处呗
Then I'll sail the Iron Fleet somewhere else.
不过 我得先把女王操了
But first I'm gonna fuck the queen.
两万人 是吗？
Twenty-thousand men, is it?
是的 陛下 路上死了一些
Yes, Your Grace. A few died in transit.
是因为他们玩骰子出老千
They cheated at dice.
也许是我出老千
Or maybe I cheated.
反正有人出了
Someone cheated.
他们打仗不怎么厉害 没了也不是什么损失
They weren't good fighters. You won't miss them.
- 马有多少？ - 两千匹
Horses? Two thousand.
大象呢
And elephants?
呃 禀告陛下 我们没有大象
Uh, no elephants, Your Grace.
真让人失望
That's disappointing.
我听说黄金团是有大象的
I was told the Golden Company had elephants.
大象确实是非凡的猛兽 陛下
They are excellent beasts, Your Grace
但不适应海上长途航行
but not well-suited to long sea voyages.
不管怎样 君临都欢迎你们的到来
In any event, you are most welcome
斯崔克兰团长
here in King's Landing, Captain Strickland.
我们期待为您作战 陛下
We look forward to fighting on your behalf, Your Grace.
那这里欢迎我吗
Am I most welcome here?
你是王室真诚的朋友
You are a true friend of the crown
也是备受尊敬的贵宾
and an honored guest.
很好
Good.
那作为真诚的朋友和尊敬的贵宾……
As a true friend and an honored guest...
格雷果·克里冈
“魔山”
我希望我们可以私下谈谈
I was hoping we could talk in private.
战争结束再提此事 我们已经达成协议了
After the war. That was our agreement.
战争也许会持续数年
Wars sometimes last years.
你想要妓女 就去花金子买
You want a whore, buy one.
你如果想要女王……
You want a queen...
就得赢得她
earn her.
我该怎么做？
How?
我已经帮她主持正义
I've given her justice,
给了她佣兵团和一支铁舰队
an army and the Iron Fleet,
然而她却没有表露出一丝爱意
yet she gives me no sign of affection.
我的心都要碎了
My heart is nearly broken.
你太放肆了
You're insolent.
- 因为无礼而被我处死的人 他们还没有你嚣张 - 他们在其他方面也不如我
-I've executed men for less. -They were lesser men.
听说 龙烧死了一千个兰尼斯特士兵
I hear the dragon burnt up a thousand Lannister men.
波隆
死了几个我最喜欢的小伙子
Burnt up some of my favorite boys.
- 是阿奇吗？ - 还有威廉
-Archie, was it? -And William.
- 那个又高又帅的威廉？- 对 就是他
-Tall handsome William? -Yeah, tall handsome William.
听说他被烧剩的骨头渣 只够盛满一个酒杯
They said what's left of him could fit in a wine glass.
我是你们见过的 唯一一个射过龙的人
I am the only man you ever met who shot a dragon.
- 真的？- 差点把它杀死了
-Did you? -Nearly killed it.
那你真英勇
That's brave.
- 那个叫艾迪的小子……   - 那个红头发的？
-That boy Eddie...  -The ginger?
还记得上一季的 Ed Sheeran 吗？
就是他 回来时脸都烧没了
That's him. Came back with his face burnt right off.
他现在没有眼皮了
He's got no eyelids now.
没眼皮他怎么睡觉啊？
How does he sleep with no eyelids?
好了 能不能别他妈聊龙的事了？
All right, can we stop talking about the fucking dragons now?
黑水河的波隆骑士
Ser Bronn of the Blackwater.
你逗我呢吧
You're kidding me.
抱歉打扰了
Apologies for the interruption,
但女王确实催促我尽快前来
but the queen did urge me to hurry.
抱歉 姑娘们
Sorry, ladies.
下次吧
Another time perhaps.
你有过空虚寂寞的时候吗 我挺喜欢年纪大的男人
You ever get lonely, I am partial to older gentlemen.
可怜的姑娘 看这梅毒病情 她活不过一年了
Poor girl. The pox will take her within the year.
- 你说哪个姑娘？ - 女王的弟弟们曾对你许诺
-Which girl? -The queen's brothers
但他们没能坚守诺言
made promises to you and broke them.
女王陛下想要弥补这个过失
Her Grace wants to rectify their mistake.
她曾给了我城堡和妻子
She once gave me a castle and a wife,
然后又全部从我手中夺走
then rectified me right out of them.
那是詹姆爵士所为 与她无关
That was Ser Jaime's doing, not hers.
如果瑟曦女王对你有所求
When Queen Cersei wants something,
她会预付你黄金
she pays in advance and in gold.
实际上 是成箱的黄金
Several chests of it, in fact.
它们正在门外的马车里等着你
Waiting for you in a wagon just outside.
所以她想杀人 又不能派自己的士兵去
So she wants to murder someone, but she can't send her soldiers.
如果她盯上的的是龙女王……
If it's the Dragon Queen she's after...
对于那个坦格利安女孩 她另有谋划
She has other plans for the Targaryen girl.
啊 好吧 那祝计划成功
Yeah, well, good luck with that.
女王的弟弟们可能不会
Our queen's brothers are unlikely
在北境历险后平安归来
to survive their Northern adventures.
但 万一他们活下来了……
But in the event that they do...
陛下一向赏罚分明
She has a keen sense of poetic justice.
这一家人都有病
That fucking family.
学城驱逐我的时候
When the Citadel expelled me,
我以为我会潦倒孤独而死
I thought I would die poor and alone,
但为了回报我的衷心侍奉  瑟曦女王封我为女王之手
but in exchange for my service, Queen Cersei made me her Hand.
如果有人能帮她除掉叛国的弟弟们
What would she do for the man
她又会如何回报呢？
who rids her of her treasonous brothers?
我本来想要大象的
I wanted those elephants.
那……
So...
我和那个胖国王比起来怎么样？
how do I compare to the fat king?
你在侮辱我的先夫吗？
You're insulting my late husband?
那你被冒犯了吗？
Are you offended?
劳勃每晚都和不同的妓女过夜
Robert had a different whore every night
但还是不懂该怎样对待女人的身体
but he still didn't know his way around a woman's body.
跟弑君者比呢？
And the Kingslayer?
你真是喜欢作死啊
You enjoy risking your neck, don't you?
活着没意思
Life is boring.
但你还有点意思 这一点我承认
You're not boring, I'll give you that.
我是否取悦了女王陛下？
Do I please the queen?
你可能是我遇见的最傲慢无礼的人
You might be the most arrogant man I've ever met.
我喜欢
I like that.
但现在我想独自待着
But now I want to be alone.
我要让你怀上我的王子
I'm going to put a prince in your belly.
席恩·葛雷乔伊
攸伦保不住铁群岛
Euron can't defend the Iron Islands,
现在他和全部人马 舰队都在君临
not if he's in King's Landing with all his men and his ships.
我们可以趁机夺回铁群岛
We can take our home back.
丹妮莉丝去了北境
Daenerys went north.
如果北境失守
Daenerys will need somewhere to retreat
那丹妮莉丝就需要一条退路
if they can't hold the North.
而尸鬼到不了铁群岛
Somewhere the dead can't go.
我奉你为女王 听你号令 追随于你
You're my queen. I go where you command.
你想去临冬城
You want to go to Winterfell.
为史塔克家战斗
To fight for the Starks.
去吧
Go.
逝者不死
What is dead may never die.
不管怎样 干掉那些杂种
But kill the bastards anyway.
欢迎回家 小姐
Welcome back, my lady.
请跟我来……
If you'd follow me...
卡史塔克家来了
The Karstarks.
他们的纹章不错
One of the better sigils.
反正比洋葱好看
Beats an onion, anyway.
无可辩驳
Can't argue with that.
史塔克和卡史塔克在战场上互相残杀
Not so long ago, the Starks and the Karstarks
才过去没多久
were slaughtering each other on the battlefield.
是琼恩·雪诺让两家重归于好
Jon Snow brought peace to the houses.
女王陛下对此感激不尽
And our queen is grateful.
这自然很好 但重点不是这个
Her gratitude is lovely, but that's not my point.
北境效忠于琼恩·雪诺 不是丹妮莉丝
The Northmen are loyal to Jon Snow, not to her.
他们根本不认识她
They don't know her.
自由民也不认她
The Free Folk don't know her.
我在北境呆的时间不短 我跟你说
I've been up here a while, and I'm telling you,
这儿的人倔得像牛
they're stubborn as goats.
你得自己去争得他们的忠心
You want their loyalty, you have to earn it.
你有什么好建议 说来听听
I sense that you're leading to a proposal.
我的建议 就是联姻
A proposal is what I'm proposing.
如果我们侥幸打败夜王 活了下来
On the off chance that we survive the Night King,
如果七大王国能迎来
what if the Seven Kingdoms,
史上他妈的第一次
for once in their whole shit history,
由一位公正的女性和一位正直的男性共治的时代 会怎样呢？
were ruled by a just woman and an honorable man?
他俩确实是天生一对
They do make a handsome couple.
你高估我们的影响力了
You overestimate our influence.
他们才不会听这些单身老男人的话
Jon and Daenerys don't want to listen to lonely old men.
我可不是老男人
I'm not that old.
没他那么老
Not as old as him.
我们的女王很尊敬长者的智慧
Our queen respects the wisdom of age.
当然
Of course she does.
这就叫敬而远之
Respect is how the young keep us at a distance,
好让我们不去忠言逆耳
so we don't remind them of an unpleasant truth.
什么忠言
What is that?
没有什么是永恒的
Nothing lasts.
嘿！
Hey!
你妹妹不喜欢我
Your sister doesn't like me.
因为她不了解你
She doesn't know you.
那我这样说你可能好受一些
If it makes you feel any better,
小时候她也不喜欢我
she didn't like me either when we were growing up.
我并不是要她把我当作朋友
She doesn't need to be my friend...
但我是她的女王
but I am her queen.
如果她不尊敬我……
If she can't respect me...
今天它们吃了多少
只有十八只山羊 十一只绵羊
什么事
What's the matter?
龙的胃口不太好
The dragons are barely eating.
雷哥
丹妮莉丝的绿龙
它们怎么了
What's wrong with them?
它们不喜欢北境
They don't like the North.
上来啊
Go on.
我不会骑龙啊
I don't know how to ride a dragon.
没人生来就会 骑上来就行了
Nobody does. Until they ride a dragon.
要是它不想让我坐上去呢
What if he doesn't want me to?
那我就会感谢你一直以来的陪伴 琼恩·雪诺
Then I've enjoyed your company, Jon Snow.
该抓哪啊？
What do I hold onto?
能抓什么抓什么吧
Whatever you can.
啊！
Aah!
你毁了我对骑马的兴趣
You've completely ruined horses for me.
我们可以在这儿呆一千年
We could stay a thousand years...
谁也找不到我们
no one would find us.
到那时候 我们就很老了
We'd be pretty old.
对南方姑娘来说 这里确实太冷了
It's cold up here for a southern girl.
那还不给你的女王一点温暖
So keep your queen warm.
别怕 没事儿
Don't be afraid.
这个不错
That's good.
- 詹德利？- 他在这儿
- Gendry? - He's here.
用龙晶锻造这么大一把斧子可不容易
It isn't easy making a blade that big with dragonglass.
你不是说自己很厉害吗 嗯？
You're saying you're good, is that it?
我只是说 这材料挺棘手的——
I'm just saying it's a tricky material to--
你知道给野人打造武器的都是什么人吗？
You know who makes weapons for the wildlings?
不是瘸子就是混蛋
Cripples and cocksuckers.
- 你是哪一类 - 放过他吧
- Which one are you? - Leave him be.
我听说你来了
I heard you were here.
你把我扔下等死
You left me to die.
我还先抢劫了你呢
First I robbed you.
你可真是个冷血小贱人啊
You're a cold little bitch, aren't you?
看来你就是靠这一点才活到今天的
Guess that's why you're still alive.
你为他打的那把斧子真不错
That was a nice ax you made for him.
你比以前更厉害了
You've gotten better.
哈 谢谢 你也一样
Yeah, thanks. So have you.
我的意思是 你看起来不错
I mean, you look good.
谢了 你也是
Thanks. So do you.
要不是太冷 在这地方长大还挺不错的
It's not a bad place to grow up, if it wasn't so cold.
那就靠炉子近一点儿
Stay close to that forge, then.
- 这是命令吗？史塔克小姐 - 别这么叫我
- Is that a command, Lady Stark? - Don't call me that.
遵命 小姐阁下
As you wish, milady.
我想要这个
Here's my wish.
你能做出来吗？
Can you make it?
你用这东西做什么用？
What do you need something like this for?
你到底能不能做出来？
Can you make it or not?
你不是已经有一把剑了 这又是什么？
You already have a sword. What's that?
这是瓦雷利亚钢
It's Valyrian steel.
我就知道你也是个有钱姑娘
I always knew you were just another rich girl.
说得好像你还认识其他有钱姑娘一样
You don't know any other rich girls.
请进
Come in.
葛洛佛大人祝我们好运
Lord Glover wishes us good fortune,
但他会和手下人留在深林堡
but he's staying in Deepwood Motte with his men.
“葛洛佛家族将继续效忠于史塔克家族
"House Glover will stand behind House Stark
一如千年以来那样”
as we have for a thousand years."
他之前不就是这么说的吗？
Isn't that what he said?
他说的是 “我将效忠于琼恩·雪诺”
"I will stand behind Jon Snow," he said.
“北境之王”
"The King in the North."
我们需要盟友 我告诉过你
I told you we needed allies.
可你没说过会放弃王位
You didn't tell me you were going to abandon your crown.
我从没想过要当什么国王
I never wanted a crown.
我只想要保护北境
All I wanted was to protect the North.
我带回家两支军队 两条龙
I brought two armies home with me, two dragons.
还有一位坦格利安家的女王
And a Targaryen queen.
你真觉得
Do you think
没有她 我们能打败尸鬼大军？
we can beat the Army of the Dead without her?
珊莎 我亲自与它们战斗过 两次
I fought them, Sansa. Twice.
如果你在意的是头衔称谓
You want to worry about who holds what title,
那我就告诉你 这无关紧要
I'm telling you it doesn't matter.
没有她 我们连一丝胜算都没有
Without her, we don't stand a chance.
你相信我吗？哪怕一点儿
Do you have any faith in me at all?
你懂我的 一如既往
You know I do.
她会是一位优秀的女王
She'll be a good queen.
对我们所有人而言
For all of us.
她不像她的父亲那样
She's not her father.
对 她可漂亮多了
No, she's much prettier.
你屈膝下跪 究竟是为了拯救北境
Did you bend the knee to save the North
还是因为你爱上了她？
or because you love her?
噢！
Oh!
山姆威尔·塔利
就是你吗？
So you're the man?
呃
Um...
女王陛下 您说的是？
Which man am I, Your Grace?
无人能够挽救乔拉爵士的性命时 是你挺身而出
The one who saved Ser Jorah when no one else could.
他们可以出手 只是不愿罢了
They could, they just wouldn't.
当我夺回王位时
I'll have to make some changes
会对学城进行一些调整
in the Citadel when I take my throne.
你尽心竭力的服务配得上一流的回报
A great service merits a great reward.
噢 能够为您服务就是我的荣幸了 陛下
Oh, it's my honor to serve you, Your Grace.
很好 不过我总能赏赐给你一些东西吧
Well, there must be something I could give you.
恕我冒昧
If it's not too much trouble,
我想请求您的宽恕
I could use a pardon.
你犯下了什么罪过呢？
For what crime?
呃
Um--
我从学城借走了一些书
I borrowed a few books from the Citadel.
还有一把剑
And also a sword.
- 剑也是学城的？- 不 剑属于我的家族
- From the Citadel? - From my family.
那把剑是塔利家族的 代代相传
It's been in House Tarly for generations.
最后本该传到我的手上
It would've been mine anyway, eventually,
但我的父亲另有打算
but my father had other ideas.
令尊不会是蓝道·塔利吧？
Not Randyll Tarly?
您认识他？
You know him?
若他那时向我屈膝投降
I offered to let him retain his lands and titles
我会允许他保留封地和头衔
if he bent the knee.
可他拒绝了
He refused.
那
Well...
既然如此 我弟弟就是角陵伯爵了
At least I'll be allowed home again,
至少我还可以回家吧
now that my brother's the lord.
他和令尊坚持同样的立场
Your brother stood with your father.
嗯
Hm.
陛下 谢谢您
Thank you, Your Grace.
把这一切告诉我
For telling me.
那我
And m--
- 我可否…… - 退下吧
- May I...? - Of course.
你在这里做什么？
What are you doing out here?
等 等一个老朋友
Waiting, for an old friend.
是时候告诉琼恩真相了
It's time to tell Jon the truth.
不 我不行
No, no.
你是他的弟弟 不该由你来告诉他吗
You're his brother.Shouldn't you tell him?
我不是他的弟弟
I'm not his brother.
他信任你胜过任何人
He trusts you more than anyone.
现在是时候了
Now's the time.
山姆？
Sam?
抱歉 我知道我不应该下到这来
I'm sorry, I know I'm not supposed to be down here.
- 你一直在躲着我吗？ - 当然不是
- Were you hiding from me? - Of course not.
你怎么会在临冬城？
What are you doing in Winterfell?
难道你已经读完了学城所有的书？
Or did you read every book in the Citadel already?
怎么了？
What's wrong?
吉莉？她没事吧？
Gilly? Is she all right?
- 她没事 - 小山姆呢？
- She's good. - Little Sam?
你不知道吗？
Don't you know?
知道什么？
Know what?
丹妮莉丝……
Daenerys...
她处死了我父亲还有弟弟
she executed my father and brother.
他们是她的俘虏
They were her prisoners.
她没告诉你
She didn't tell you.
对此我很遗憾
I'm so sorry.
我们需要结束这场战争
We need to end this war.
换做你 也会那么做吗？
Would you have done it?
我也处死过不服从我的人
Well, I've executed men who disobeyed me.
但你也宽恕过很多人
You've also spared men.
几千拒绝屈膝臣服的野人
Thousands of wildlings when they refused to kneel.
那时我又不是国王
I wasn't a king.
不 你是
But you were.
你一直都是
You've always been.
我已经放弃王位了 山姆
I gave up my crown, Sam.
我已屈膝臣服
I bent the knee.
不再是北境之王了
I'm not King in the North anymore.
我说的不是北境之王
I'm not talking about the King in the North.
我说的是他妈整个七大王国的国王
I'm talking about the King of the bloody Seven Kingdoms.
布兰和我查清楚了
Bran and I worked it out.
我拿到一本总主教的日记 布兰有……
I had a High Septon's diary.Bran had...
先不提布兰有什么了
whatever Bran has.
你到底在说什么？
What are you talking about?
你的母亲
Your mother...
是莱安娜·史塔克
was Lyanna Stark.
而你的父亲……
And your father...
你的亲生父亲
your real father
是雷加·坦格利安
was Rhaegar Targaryen.
你从来都不是什么私生子
You've never been a bastard.
你真名为伊耿·坦格利安 铁王座真正的继承人
You're Aegon Targaryen,true heir to the Iron Throne.
抱歉 我知道这些很难接受
I'm sorry,I know it's a lot to take in.
我父亲是我见过的最信守荣誉之人
My father was the most honorable man I ever met.
你却告诉我他骗了我一辈子
You're saying he lied to me all my life.
不
No.
你父亲 好吧 奈德·史塔克
Your father-- Well, Ned Stark.
他向你母亲承诺会一直保护你
He promised your mother he'd always protect you.
而他确实做到了 劳勃如果知道了真相一定会杀了你
And he did. Robert would have murdered you if he knew.
你才是真正的国王
You're the true king.
伊耿·坦格利安六世
Aegon Targaryen,Sixth of His Name,
全境守护者 还有那一串头衔
Protector of the Realm,all of it.
- 丹妮莉丝是我们的女王 - 可她不该是
- Daenerys is our queen. - She shouldn't be.
- 你这是叛国 - 我这是说出真相
- That's treason. - It's the truth.
你能为保护子民而放弃王位
You gave up your crown to save your people.
她也能做到吗？
Would she do the same?
托蒙德
“巨人克星”
贝里·唐德利恩
“闪电大王”
退后 这家伙眼睛是蓝的！
Stay back, he's got blue eyes!
我的眼睛一直是蓝的！
I've always had blue eyes!
艾迪森·托勒特
“忧郁的艾迪” 守夜人指挥官
你找到什么人了吗？
Did you find anyone?
安柏家的男孩
The Umber boy.
这是个讯息
It's a message.
夜王留下的讯息
From the Night King.
他的大军已经先我们一步去往临冬城了 而我们只能步行
His army's between us and Winterfell. We're on foot.
我们是从黑城堡骑马来的
We rode down from Castle Black.
咱们可以两人骑一匹马
We can double up on the horses.
如果马能撑得住 我们可以赶在尸鬼大军之前抵达
If the horses last, we'll get there before the dead.
只能说但愿
We just have to hope
夜王不会先到一步
the Night King doesn't come first.
走起来！往前走！
Keep moving! Straight up!
跟上！别落后！
Stay together!Don't fall behind!
詹姆·兰尼斯特
“弑君者”
衣柜字幕组出品
冰火中文维基：http://asoiaf.huijiwiki.com/
本集关键字：黄金团 临冬城
当我还是个孩子的时候 哥哥就给我讲过
When I was a child,my brother would tell me
一个睡前故事 关于杀害我父王的凶手
a bedtime story, about the man who murdered our father.
还有我们未来处置那个凶手的各种手段
About all the things we would do to that man.
《权力的游戏》下集预告
你根本不应该信任瑟曦
You never should have trusted Cersei.
你也不应该
You never should have either.
死神……
Death...
他有千张面孔 我很期待会会这一张
it's got many faces, I look forward to seeing this one.
我们还有多久？
How long do we have?
只到明天的太阳升起之前
Before the sun comes up tomorrow.